Mohsin Haider

https://mohsinh.com/

OVERVIEW

Creative and collaborative undergraduate with practical experience in design, prototyping, and mechanical development. Demonstrated ability in communicating complex topics in a clear and effective way to a broad audience.

• Design Tools: Fusion 360, SolidWorks, Illustrator, Inkscape

Prototyping: Laser Cutting, Waterjet, 3D Printing, CNC Milling, CAM

Programming: Python, Arduino, GitHub, Heroku, some experience with MATLAB

• Soft Skills: Communication, Problem Solving, Flexibility

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering

Pratt School of Engineering, Duke University, Durham, NC

High School Diploma

Raleigh Charter High School, Raleigh, NC

Expected May 2022 GPA: 3.8

May 2018

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

DesignHub, Duke University

Design Engineer

Durham, NC Aug 2019 — Present

- Design products, mechanisms, and prototypes for DesignHub clients as a contract engineer
- Develop important client ideas into functional products through structured project management
- Currently working on a smart toilet seat (see below)

Pratt School of Engineering, Duke University

Lab Teaching Assistant for EGR101

Durham, NC

Aug 2019 — Present

- Serve as a lab teaching assistant for EGR101, Pratt's introductory design course for engineers
- · Educate students on usage of prototyping tools and proper fabrication methods while maintaining safety
- Provide design advice to freshman at various skill and experience levels

Innovation Co-Lab Studio, Duke University

Durham, NC

Student Technician

Aug 2018 — Aug 2019

- Troubleshooted, repaired, and maintained fleet of 75 3D printers in Duke University's Co-Lab Studio (Makerspace)
- Instructed students on how to operate 3D printers, water jet cutters, laser cutters, and CNC machines
- Advised wide variety of clients on best methods to utilize Co-Lab machines for their projects

PROJECTS (see more on website above)

Duke Department of Ophthalmology

Durham, NC

Project: Eye Forceps

Nov 2019 — Present

- Developing a patent-bound novel surgery tool that will make a common surgery quicker and more efficient
- Creating animations, simulations, and drawings for patent documentation and idea communication
- Designing renders and functional prototypes of the tool using SolidWorks and advance additive manufacturing

The David Lab at Duke University

Durham, NC

Project: Smart Toilet

Jun 2019 — Present

- Leading mechanical development and testing for a patent-pending, market-bound biomedical device
- Designing and creating sensor mechanisms, device prototypes, automated testing rigs and validation devices
- Gaining experience in biomedical device design and regulations, patents, and mechanical design

RELEVANT COURSEWORK

- Calculus I, II, and III
- Fundamental Engineering Design
- Mechanics of Solids

- Linear Algebra, Differential Equations
- Introductory Programming
- Physics: Mechanics, Electricity, Magnetism